# **David Biertimpel**

# **Computer Vision Research Engineer**

@ david.biertimpel@protonmail.com () /dbtmpl

/dbtmpl

**4** +49 1515 6187453 in /david-biertimpel

% dbtmpl.github.io **♥** Berlin, Germany

### **Interests**

I have a passion for computer vision research and applications that positively impact people's daily lives. I enjoy crafting inductive biases that reflect the structure of the problem at hand and allow for data-efficient solutions. I bring excellent skills in theoretical machine learning, combined with a strong background in computer science, software development and psychology.

# **Education**

# MSc Artificial Intelligence, GPA: 8.5 (excellent) **University of Amsterdam**

₩ Sep 2018 – Jan 2021

Amsterdam, NL

- · Research master's degree with a strong focus on the theoretical aspects of machine learning and information theory.
- Mathematically deriving and implementing most major machine learning concepts including Gaussian processes, MCMC, variational inference, GANs, RNNs/LSTMs, GNNs, normalizing flows, Learning to rank, ICA, among others.
- Implementing applications of different computer vision concepts such as intrinsic image decomposition, epipolar geometry and 3D reconstruction, among others.
- Thesis: Learning Foreground Cues for Novel Objects in Partially Supervised Instance Segmentation @ TomTom.

### BSc Human Computer Interaction, GPA: 8.1 (good) **University of Hamburg**

Oct 2014 - Aug 2018

**♀** Hamburg, DE

- Strongly interdisciplinary degree combining the fields of computer science and psychology.
- Strong computer science background with focus on software engineering, algorithms & DS and theoretical informatics.
- Thesis: Implementing a deictic gesture interface with the humanoid robot NICO. Final grade: 10.0 – ://github.com/.
- Project: Multi-user collaboration in VR. Implementing a network infrastructure with C# and Unity -: //uni-hamburg.de/.

# Skills

#### Programming:

- Fluent in Python including PyTorch, SciPy, OpenCV.
- Fluent in JavaScript including Tensorflow.js, React, Webpack.
- Experienced in software engineering and compl. analysis.
- Further experience with Matlab, Java, C#, C++ and Scheme.

#### Machine Learning Research:

- Fluent in different machine learning workflows including data mining, implementing models from scratch and training models on computer clusters.
- Excellent skills in academic writing. Experienced in academia including writing, revising and publishing papers.

#### Languages:

• Native German speaker, proficient in English.

# **Work Experience**

#### Computer Vision Engineer

#### Figment -: //tryfigment.com/

🛗 Feb 2021 – Sep 2021, Full-Time

Remote / Amsterdam, NL

- R&D on real-time person segmentation models running on edge devices.
- Designing and implementing a MLflow training pipeline based on AWS.
- Developing the backend of Figment a JavaScript SaaS application offering virtual background and augmented reality features for video calls.
- Deploying person segmentation models on Nvidia Xavier edge GPUs.
- Experience with PyTorch, TensorRT, MLflow, Tensorflow.js, Webpack, AWS.

#### Machine Learning Research Intern

#### TomTom, Autonomous Driving Team -: //tomtom.com/

🛗 Jan 2020 – Nov 2020, Full-Time

Amsterdam, NL

- Working on instance segmentation with the goal to craft inductive biases that facilitate generalization to weakly annotated classes.
- Designing, implementing and evaluating computer vision architectures. Research led to the creation of OPMask (ICCV 2021) -: //github.com/.
- Presenting papers in the weekly object detection reading group.
- Contributing to open-source (Detectron2) ://github.com/.
- Experience with PyTorch, OpenCV, Detectron2, Slurm.

#### Research Intern

#### Spinoza Centre for Neuroimaging -: //spinozacentre.nl/

🛗 Jun 2019 – Jul 2019, Part-Time

Amsterdam, NL

- Analyzing fMRI data from the Human Connectome Project corresponding to naturalistic video sequences to understand connectivity in brain regions.
- Automatically annotating video sequences with object detection architectures such as RetinaNet and Faster R-CNN.
- Experience with PyTorch, NIPY, Pycortex and the Connectome Workbench.

# **Volunteer Experience**

#### Volunteer Coordinator

### Grace House CC, Globalteer via GIZ -://giz.de/en/

Aug 2012 – Jul 2013

- · Onboarding and supporting short-term volunteers.
- Organizing a Cambodian youth group in the evenings & contributing to the Globalteer sports program.

# **Publications**

- David Biertimpel et al. "Prior to Segment: Foreground Cues for Weakly Annotated Classes in Partially Supervised Instance Segmentation". In: The IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV). 2021.
- [2] Doreen Jirak et al. "Solving visual object ambiguities when pointing: an unsupervised learning approach". In: Neural Computing and Applications. June 2020.